什么？你刚才...什么？
What? What did you... What?
我仍然爱着你
I still love you.
我知道我甚至不该来这里告诉你
I know I shouldn't even be here telling you this.
你跟钱德在一起 我很喜欢他
You're with Chandler, a guy I really like.
你说他是异性恋 我就相信你
You say he's straight, I'll believe you.
但见到你之后 我知道我不说 会后悔一辈子
After seeing you, I knew if I didn't tell you I'd always regret it.
放弃你是我所做过最蠢的事
Letting you go was the stupidest thing I ever did.
你不该到厨房来的
You're really not supposed to be back here.
我知道 对不起 我知道时机地点都不对 但是...
I'm sorry. I know this is the wrong time and the wrong place...
我一定要说
but I had to tell you.
我想跟你共度一生 我想娶你
I want to spend my life with you and marry you.
我想跟你生儿育女
I want to have kids with you.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
这里为什么没摆椅子？
Why don't they put chairs back here?
我知道我很扯 来不及了吗？
I know this is crazy, but am I too late?
没错 来不及了 这些话你3年前怎么不说？
Yes, you're too late. Where was all this three years ago?
我知道 我是个白痴
I know. I was an idiot.
我也想忘记你 真的
And I tried to forget you. I really did.
我们去年吃完饭 我跑去非洲待了6个月想忘记你
After we had lunch last year, I spent six months in Africa trying to forget.
- 你去非洲做什么？ - 帮助盲童
- What were you doing in Africa?     - Working with blind kids.
你折磨我嘛
What are you doing to me?
怎么说呢...
Look, I...
很抱歉 我们之间是不可能的
I'm sorry, but it's not gonna happen.
好 我会离开 再也不会来烦你
That's fine. I'll walk away. And I'll never bother you again.
但前提是 你要告诉我 钱德也愿意给你这一切
Only if you tell me Chandler's willing to give you everything I am.
他愿意...
Well, he is. I mean...
没错 他成天把婚姻挂在嘴边
marriage is all he talks about.
老天
My goodness.
事实上是我在让他等
In fact, I'm the one making him wait.
- 是吗？ - 对
- You are?     - Yeah.
- 为什么？ - 为什么？
- Why?     - Why?
因为政府的阴谋
Because of the government.
老友记 第六季 第二十五集 本季终
很棒吧？
Isn't it incredible?
摩妮卡和钱德要结婚了
Monica and Chandler are getting married.
就是啊 他们会很幸福
I know. They'll be so happy together.
两个最要好的朋友坠入爱河 这种机率有多大？
Two best friends in love. How often does that happen?
- 并不太大   - 没错
- Not that often.     - No.
我好替他们开心
I'm so happy for them.
我也是 好开心
Me too. So happy for them.
我很高兴 毫无嫉妒之心
I'm so happy and not at all jealous.
- 没错 当然没有   - 嗯
- Oh, no! God, definitely not jealous.     - Mm-mm.
我可能是百分之98开心 百分之2嫉妒
I'm probably 98 percent happy and maybe 2 percent jealous.
百分之2等于没有
What's 2 percent? That's nothing.
没错
Totally.
- 我是9比1   - 我也是
- I'm like 90-10.     - Yeah. Me too.
你们有见到钱德吗？
Hey, have you guys seen Chandler?
没有 但你知道谁来找过你吗？
No. But you know who was looking for you?
坦妮尔
Tennille.
（约翰彼萨店）
关于婚姻 你昨天说的那些话...
So that marriage stuff you were saying yesterday?
- 应该不是真心话吧？ - 当然是
- You don't really believe that.     - Sure, I do.
事实上我觉得婚姻本身 就很不近人情
In fact, I think the whole concept of marriage is unnatural.
你看猪嘛 我们来看一下猪
Look at pigs. Let's take a second here and look at pigs.
猪不会有固定配偶
Pigs don't mate for life.
猪的一生可以有一百个性伴侣
A pig can have 100 sexual partners in a lifetime.
那还只是普通的猪 而不是擅长运动的猪
And that's just an ordinary pig, not even a pig that's good at sports.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是说 你可能 永远都不想结婚？
Are you telling me you may never want to get married?
话不能说死 不过应该是...
Never say never, but, probably...
永远不会
yeah, never.
天哪
Oh, my God.
那我们在干什么？现在是怎样？
Then what are we even doing? What is this?
干嘛对我施压？
Whoa, whoa, whoa, what is all this pressure?
这是某种新策略吗？
Is this some new strategy?
你别再搞尔虞我诈那一套了
Why don't you put down your copy of The Rules, huh, man-trap?
你知道吗？我要走了
You know what? I gotta go.
放心 我自有打算
It's okay. I got a plan.
- 我们会找到真爱的   - 一定会的
- We're gonna find love.     - Definitely.
我对这点有信心
Yeah, I'm pretty confident about that.
所以我可以有八成 替摩妮卡和钱德高兴
That's what makes it so easy to be 80 percent happy for Monica and Chandler.
- 不过要是有保障就好了   - 什么意思？
- Would be nice to have a guarantee.     - What do you mean?
有些人不是会跟朋友约定...
Some people make deals with a friend.
要是两个人到了40都还单身 他们就结婚
Like if neither of them are married by 40, they marry each other.
- 你是指备胎？ - 没错
- You mean a backup?     - Exactly.
我已经找好了
Yeah, yeah. I've got that.
- 你找好了？ - 嗯哼
- You do?     - Mm-hm.
- 是谁？ - 乔伊
- Who?     - Joey?
- 乔伊？真的？ - 对
- Joey? Are you serious?     - Yeah.
真的 我好几年前就锁定他了
Yeah, I locked him in years ago.
所以要是你们40岁都还单身 你就嫁给乔伊
Wait. So if neither of you are married by 40, you'll marry Joey?
对 我们握手为定
Yep. We shook on it.
不过他可不想就此打住
Yeah. But believe me, that is not how he wanted to seal the deal.
是吗？
Seriously?
对 他说的是...
I think his exact words were...
真迷人
Charming.
- 他只是个备胎   - 对啊
- Ah, he's just a backup.     - Yeah.
摩妮卡
Hey, Monica.
你有见到瑞秋？或是镜子吗？
Have you seen Rachel? Or a mirror?
这是我的船长装 酷吧？
It's for my boat. Cool, huh?
很酷
Yeah, it's great.
怎么了？告诉船长吧
What's the matter? Talk to the captain.
我发现这段感情又是死路一条
Just realizing I'm in a dead-end relationship.
钱德欺负你是吧？
Chandler's giving you a hard time?
我又不是明天就要结婚 我只是想知道...
I don't want to get married tomorrow. But I want to believe...
我不是在原地打转 浪费时问
we're going somewhere, that I'm not wasting my time.
- 你也了解钱德   - 我已经不了解钱德了
- You know Chandler.     - No, I don't know Chandler.
完全不了解 仿佛有什么事变了
Not anymore. It's like something's changed.
也许是你变了？
Maybe you changed.
我才没变
I didn't change.
也许问题就在这里
Maybe that's the problem.
- 什么？ - 钱德很复杂
- What?     - Chandler is a complex fellow.
不太可能娶妻
One who is unlikely to take a wife.
他在想什么？他以为我会空等下去吗？
Does he think I'll just wait around for nothing?
面对现实吧 钱德反对婚姻
Face it. Chandler is against marriage.
他是不会变了
And always will be.
有些人可是真心想娶我
Well, there's some people who do want to marry me.
- 有吗？ - 有 理查
- There are?     - Yeah. Richard.
理查说他想娶你？
Richard said he wants to marry you?
- 而钱德说他痛恨婚姻？ - 没错
- And Chandler says he hates marriage?     - That's right.
钱德热爱婚姻
Chandler loves marriage!
你刚刚才说他痛恨婚姻
You just told me he hates marriage!
说他很复杂 不太可能娶妻
That he's a complex fellow who's unlikely to take a wife!
说他反对婚姻 而且永远不会变
That he's against marriage and always will be!
你的解读是这样？
You got that from what I said?
- 瑞秋   - 帅哥
- Rach.     - Hey, you.
- 请进   - 谢谢
- Hey, come on in.     - Thank you.
很遗憾你跟伊丽莎白分手了
I'm so sorry to hear about you and Elizabeth.
谢谢 我以为 我们能克服万难 不过...
Thanks. Yeah, I really thought we'd be able to make it work.
这大概是命中注定的
I guess it just wasn't meant to be.
是啊 爱情...
Yeah. Love.
爱情真是微妙
It's a tricky business, isn't it?
是啊
I guess so.
我们要不要来做个约定
So, what do you say we make a pact?
要是我们到了40都还单身 我们就结婚
If you and I are both single by 40, we get married.
我们已经熟悉 喜欢对方...
I mean, we know each other, we like each other...
我们已经上过床 不会有意外
we've already slept together, so there'll be no surprises there.
不会觉得"搞什么？"
No, like, "What's that?"
- 你想找我当备胎？ - 没错
- Oh, you want me to be your backup.     - Exactly.
可是我已经有备胎了
Oh, yeah. I already have one.
- 谁？ - 菲比
- Who?     - Phoebe.
菲比？
Phoebe?
但是她说乔伊是她的备胎
But she just said Joey is her backup.
才不是呢
Oh, I don't think so.
罗斯 我刚跟她聊过 她说她和乔伊约好了
I just spoke with her. She said that she and Joey made a deal.
不可能的 我们几年前早就约好了
That's impossible. We have had a deal for years.
还握手为定
We shook on it.
只不过她觉得握手还不够...
Although, believe me, she wanted to do a lot more than that.
你跑到哪儿去了？
Where have you been?
我在跟教授做椰子电话
I was making a coconut phone with the Professor.
理查跟摩妮卡说他想娶她
Richard told Monica he wants to marry her.
- 什么？ - 就是啊 我直在找你
- What?     - I've been looking for you.
叫你别玩了
Stop messing with her!
可是这双鞋子跑一跑就掉
And I would have if these damn boat shoes wouldn't keep flying off!
- 我的天啊   - 就是啊 烂死了
- Oh, my God!     - I know! They suck!
他不该向我的女朋友求婚 该求婚的人是我
He's not supposed to ask her to marry him! I am!
- 我知道   - 那...
- I know!     - What...?
你知道吗？我要去找他 好好教训他一顿
You know what I'll do? I'll go over there and kick his ass!
你愿意帮忙吗？
Will you help me?
钱德 被他海扁一顿不是办法
Look, us getting our asses kicked is not a solution.
知道吗？
Okay?
- 赶快去找摩妮卡吧   - 你说的对 好
- Look, just go and find Monica.     - You're right.
我去拿戒指...
I'm gonna get the ring...
我要找到她
I'll go find her...
直接向她求婚
and I'll propose!
老兄 老兄 老兄
Dude! Dude! Dude!
你的椰子电话 也许很适合摆在船上
That coconut phone might be good for the boat.
嘿
Hi.
我不知道我来干什么
I don't know why I'm here.
我又没问
I didn't ask.
你要进来吗？
You want to come in?
不知道
I don't know.
好吧
Oh, okay.
那我把门开着 回去坐下
I'll just leave the door open and go sit on the couch.
钱德真是个白痴
Chandler is such an idiot!
要喝点酒吗？
Drink?
- 好 我要威士忌加...   - 冰块和莱姆片？
- Scotch on the...     - Rocks with a twist?
我记得
I remember.
- 还在抽雪茄？ - 呃...
- You still smoking cigars?     - Uh...
没有 那是艺术
No, no. That's art.
如果你不喜欢 我可以把艺术熄掉
If it bothers you, I can put my art out.
没关系
No, that's okay.
摩妮卡...
So, Monica...
我问你一件事
let me ask you a question.
我们分手后...
Since we broke up, do you ever...
你想过我吗？
think about me?
我两个月前还想到你
Actually, I thought about you a couple months ago.
- 是吗？ - 不过是因为...
- Really?     - Yeah, but it's because I...
我去做眼睛检查 又不喜欢我的新医生
had an eye exam, and I don't like my new eye doctor.
- 是谁？ - 爱德华奈夫斯基
- Who is it?     - Edward Nevsky.
他的确很差
Yeah, he's no good.
你有想过...
Do you ever think about me in...
非眼科医生的我吗？
a non-eye-doctor way?
没有
No.
啊
Ah.
因为忘记你 是我这辈子做过最难的事
Because getting over you was the hardest thing I've ever had to do.
我不让自己想到你
I never let myself think about you.
哇哦
Wow.
菲比你找了乔伊和罗斯？
Phoebe, you picked Joey and Ross?
你不能有两个备胎
You can't have two backups!
当然可以
Of course I can.
眼光独到才会替备胎找备胎
It's just good sense to back up your backup.
- 我已经折损钱德了   - 什么？
- Look, I've already lost Chandler.     - What?
喂 菲比
Hey, Phoebe!
我们都是你的备胎？
We're both backups?
菲比 你怎么可以这样？
How could you do this to me?
我不知道你们在抱怨什么 你们都知道这个状况
What are you complaining about? You were both aware of the situation.
- 我不知道   - 我们不知道
- I was not!     - No, we weren't!
婚后你们可不能这样顶嘴
This kind of back talk isn't gonna fly when we're married.
菲比 你不能独占他们 你得选一个
You can't have both. Pick one.
- 选我   - 不 选我
- Pick me!     - No, pick me!
我不想当老处女
I don't want to end up an old maid.
好吧 我看看
Well, let's see.
罗斯是个好爸爸
Ross is a good father.
但是...
But...
乔伊有船 好难选喔
Joey has a boat. This is hard.
太扯了 我要换成瑞秋
This is crazy. I want to switch to Rachel.
我也要换成瑞秋
I want to switch too.
不 等一下 等一下
No, wait! Okay, just wait!
你们别急着做决定
Wait, guys. Don't make any rash decisions.
记得我的承诺吧？
Remember my promise:
结婚之后 1星期3次
If we get married, three times a week.
天哪 菲比
Oh, my God. Phoebe...
我是在说按摩
I'm talking about massages.
我不是
No, I'm not.
我知道该怎么解决了 办法就是...
I know how to settle this. Here's what we'll do.
我在一张纸巾上
I'll write "Joey"...
写"乔伊"
on one napkin.
一张纸巾上写"罗斯"
And I'm going to write "Ross" on the other napkin...
然后我们一人选一张
and we'll pick one.
那个人就是我们的备胎
That person will be our backup. Here we go.
- 很公平   - 那好
- That sounds fair.     - All right.
我来弄乱
Good. Switching them up.
哦...
Ooh...
- 选一边   - 左边
- Pick one.     - Left.
- 谢谢   - 不客气
- Thank you.     - You're welcome.
- 罗斯   - 乔伊
- Ross.     - Joey.
- 我们交换好了   - 没错
- We should just switch.     - Absolutely.
我想念这间房子...
I miss this apartment.
这才是大人的房子
Now, this is a grownup's apartment.
- 我应该跟大人在一起   - 你懂吧
- I should be with a grownup, you know?     - Yeah.
懂啊 你是说 你要跟比较成熟的人在一起
You're saying you need to be with someone more mature.
也许是一个...
Maybe someone with...
有医师执照的人
a license to practice medicine.
或是有胡子的人
Or a mustache.
说真的 我不是小孩子了
Let's face it. I'm not a kid anymore.
我需要一个目标相同的人
I need to be with someone who wants the same things.
来我工作的地方跟我示爱 我要的是那样
Coming to my work and telling me you love me, I want that!
吃饭时聊猪的性爱 我不要那样
Talking about pig sex over lunch, I don't want that!
很公平
I think that's fair.
公平？别跟我提公平
Fair? Please. Don't even talk to me about fair.
公平的意思是 当年你想娶我...
Fair would've been you wanting to marry me then.
或是钱德现在想娶我
Or Chandler wanting to marry me now.
真的 这整件事一点也不公平
Believe me, nothing about this is fair. Nothing.
- 不公平 不公平   - 别激动
- Nothing! Nothing!     - It's okay.
嗨 嘘
Hey. Shh.
不公平
Nothing.
不知道
I don't know.
我知道
I know.
是啊 我...
Yeah, I... I...
我得先把事情...
I have to figure...
想清楚 然后才能...
some stuff, before I can...
我懂
Yeah, I understand.
你只管慢漫想
Take as much time as you want.
10分钟 20分钟都行
Ten, 20 minutes, if you need it.
我会在这里 不会抽烟
I'll be here. Not smoking.
- 钱德   - 她人呢？
- Chandler.     - Where is she?
我可不怕你
I'm not scared of you.
她不在 请进
She's not here. And please come in.
威士忌加冰...
Scotch on the rocks...
和莱姆片 放在杯垫上？
with a twist, on a coaster.
摩妮卡 摩妮卡
Monica? Monica?
好吧 她来过 又走了
Okay, she was here. But she left.
她去哪里？
Where did she go?
她说 她要想清楚
She said she had to think things over.
天哪 我真不敢相信 我以为...我以为你是个好人
Oh, my God. I can't believe this. I thought you were a good guy.
我们又没怎样
Oh, hey. Look, nothing happened.
没怎样？没怎样？你没跟我女朋友示爱？
Nothing happened? Nothing? You didn't tell her you love her?
好吧 只有这样
Well, all right, one thing happened.
你知道你做了什么事吗？
You know what you did?
我的女朋友在想事情
My girlfriend is thinking things over.
你让我的女朋友思考
You made my girlfriend think!
我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry.
她还需要想什么？我爱她
What's to think about? I love her.
我愿意给她 你不愿意给的东西
Well, apparently I'm willing to offer her things that you are not.
但是我愿意给 我只是...
I'm willing to offer her those things. This was just a plan.
故意要让她失望 等真相大白 她就会很惊喜
To throw her off so when I offered all these things, she'd be surprised.
效果真的很好
If it helps, it worked very well.
直到你半路杀出来 水泥墙
It was working till you showed up, you big tree.
这样不公平
This isn't fair.
你曾经有机会 你曾经有机会 结果你搞砸了
You had your chance with her, and you blew it!
现在轮到我了 我不会搞砸
This is my chance and I won't blow it...
因为我们是天生一对
because we are meant for each other.
而这一切只是个愚蠢的错误
And this has all just been one stupid mistake!
我本来打算今晚求婚的
I was gonna propose tonight.
你要求婚？
You were?
对 我还...
Yeah, I even...
准备了戒指
got a ring.
你有吗？
Did you get a ring?
没有 我没准备
No, I don't have a ring.
你去找她吧 钱德
You go get her.
我可以给你一个忠告吗？
And can I give you a piece of advice?
要是你得到她
If you do get her...
一定要好好把握
don't let her go.
相信我
Trust me.
理查...你的确是个好人
You know, Richard, you are a good guy.
我知道
I know.
真讨厌
I hate that.
- 钱德   - 持会儿再说 我得去找摩妮卡
- Dude.     - I've gotta find Monica.
她走了
She's gone.
- 什么？ - 她走了 提着个包包走了
- What?     - She had a bag and she left.
- 你在说什么？ - 她哭得很伤心
- What?     - She was crying.
说你们要的东西不一样 说她需要时间思考
She said you want different things and she needs to think.
你为什么不栏住她？不说出我的计划？
Why didn't you tell her it was a plan?
我有啊 我都说了 钱德 但是她不信
I did! I told her everything. She wouldn't believe me.
那她...
Well, where...?
她上哪儿去了？
Where did she go?
她父母家吧 我想 她叫你不要打给她
To her parents'. She said you shouldn't call.
要是我就会打
But if I were you, I would.
我居然搞砸了
Can't believe I ruined this.
我很遗憾
I am so sorry, man.
你希望是个惊喜的
You wanted it to be a surprise.
天哪
Oh, my God.
钱德...
Chandler...
我这辈子...
in all my life...
从来没想过我会这么幸运
I never thought I would be so lucky...
可以...爱上我最要好的...
as to fall in love with my best...
我最要好的...
My best...
- 所以说都是男人在求婚的嘛   - 好好好
- There's a reason why girls don't do this!     - Okay, okay, okay.
我来 我以为...
I'll do it. I thought...
等等 我一定行
Wait, I can do this.
我以为 开口的...
I thought that it mattered...
时间地点很重要
what I said or where I said it.
后来才发现...
Then I realized...
唯一重要的是你...
the only thing that matters is that you...
你让我得到超乎想像的幸福
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
所以如果你愿意...
And if you let me...
我愿意用下半生 让你跟我一样幸福
I will spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
摩妮卡...
Monica...
你愿意嫁给我吗？
will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
我就知道你应该会娶妻
I knew you were likely to take a wife!
可以进去了吗？我们快愁死了
Can we come in yet? We're dying out here!
进来 进来
Come in! Come in!
我们订婚了
We're engaged!
噢
Oh!
这是我最不嫉妒的时候
This is the least jealous I've ever been!
等等 不行啦 罗斯不在
Oh, no, wait! This is wrong! Ross isn't here!
- 噢   - 噢
- Oh.     - Oh.
他都玩三次了 知道这是怎么回事
He's done it three times. He knows what it's about!
对啊
Yeah.
# Oh, my darling #
# You were wonderful tonight #